<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc type="api" version="1.00.00">

	<chapter title="Introduction" id="intro">
		<p>
		
		</p>
		<section title="How to read this document" id="howtoread">
			<subsection title="Where to start" id="start">
			
			
			</subsection>
			<subsection title="Formatting Conventions">
				<p>
					In this documentation, you will find several types of formatting words and paragraphs, the meaning is as follows:
				</p>
				<action>
					This box contains actions that you should take, e.g. edit files, add values to the database and such.
					Used everytime you have to do something...
					If you hate to read manuals and are more the learning-by-doing type of person, you can just follow the instructions in these boxes, ignore the rest and you should have a fully running module in the end. You'll miss something then, though...
				</action>
				<caution>
					This box provides information that can prevent you from screwing something up. Used when there are common errors to be made or where i myself are constantly implementing oversights...
				</caution>
				<info>
					This box holds important additional information, resp. where to find additional information on the current subject. Used when there are more things to know than are used/told in place...
				</info>
				<todo>
					This box states TODOs still open as well as features planned for future releases.
				</todo>
				<code>This box contains program-code</code>
			</subsection>
		</section>
		<section title="What solidMatter is and what it's not" id="what">
			<p>
				solidMatter is a Web-Development-Framework in the first place.
			</p>
			<subsection title="Content Repository Aspects" id="cr">
				<p>
					
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection title="Web Development Aspects" id="wd">
			
			</subsection>
		</section>
		<section title="Why was it created?" id="why">
		
		</section>
		<section title="Past &amp; Future" id="past">
		
		</section>
	</chapter>

	<chapter title="Modes of Operation" id="">
		<section title="JCR API only" id="">
			<p>
				You may incorporate the sbCR classes to access the repository via the JCR API in the context of your application.
			</p>
			<caution>
				Not tested yet, there may be some unwanted dependencies. Also it's not the whole JCR API implemented, and there are things handled differently in sbCR!
			</caution>
		</section>
		<section title="sbCR Infrastructure" id="">
			<p>
				You may incorporate the sbCR classes to access the repository via the full sbCR API (including extensions) in the context of your application.
			</p>
			<caution>
				Not tested yet, there may be some unwanted dependencies.
			</caution>
		</section>
		<section title="Full solidMatter API" id="">
			
			
		</section>
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter title="solidMatter" id="">
		<section title="Application Layers" id="">
			<p>
				This chapter describes
			</p>
			<subsection title="Interface">
				
			</subsection>
			<subsection title="Controller">
				
			</subsection>
			<subsection title="Data Storage">
				
			</subsection>
		</section>
		<section title="Application Flow" id="">
			<subsection title="From Request to Response">
				
			</subsection>
			<subsection title="Handlers">
				
			</subsection>
		</section>
		<section title="Data Transport" id="">
			<subsection title="$_REQUEST / $_RESPONSE">
				
			</subsection>
			<subsection title="Handlers">
				
			</subsection>
			
		</section>
		<section title="Form Building" id="">
			<subsection title="The sbDOMForm Class">
				<p>
					The <class>sbDOMForm</class> class if the default method of building forms for the UI.
					It has some properties defined for the form itself (action, label, id) as well as a variable number of form elements.
					The form elements are called Inputs internally, and every element type has to be derived from the abstract <class>Input</class> class.
				</p>
				<p>
					Example for creating a simple fictional form that is used to edit customer details.
				</p>
				<code>// init form
$formCustomer = new sbDOMForm(
	'customer_details', // id
	'Edit customer details', // title
	'/customer/details/save' // action 
);

// add fields
$formCustomer->addInput('first_name;string;minlength=2;maxlength=50;required=TRUE;', '$locale/myModule/customer/firstName');
$formCustomer->addInput('last_name;string;minlength=2;maxlength=50;required=TRUE;', '$locale/myModule/customer/lastName');
$formCustomer->addInput('gender;select;', '$locale/myModule/customer/gender');
$formCustomer->addInput('email;email;required=TRUE;', '$locale/myModule/customer/email');
$formCustomer->addInput('address_postalcode;integer;maxvalue=99999;', '$locale/myModule/customer/postalcode');
$formCustomer->addInput('address_city;string;maxlength=100;', '$locale/myModule/customer/city');
$formCustomer->addInput('address_street;string;maxlength=150;', '$locale/myModule/customer/street');
$formCustomer->addInput('address_housenumber;integer;', '$locale/myModule/customer/houseNumber');
$formCustomer->addSubmit('$locale/myModule/actions/save');

// set options for gender dropdown
$aOptions['m'] = 'male';
$aOptions['f'] = 'female';	
$formCustomer->setOptions('gender', $aOptions);

// include form in output
$_RESPONSE->addData($formCustomer);
</code>
				<todo>
					Evaluate the possibilities (incl. cost/value) of richer forms.
					Forms containing more logic (e.g. show some parts only if a specific checkbox is checked) than the current 'flat' forms are a nice idea, but bear the danger of rebuilding a good portion of application logic in the interface.
				</todo>
			</subsection>
			<subsection title="Inputs">
				<todo>
					Input types should be expandable by 3rd party modules, currently they're a fixed sbSystem matter.
					There has to be some System::registerInputType() or similar, perhaps namespaces make sense then (e.g. different apps with 'customer' inputfield).
				</todo>
			</subsection>
			<subsection title="Form Validation">
				
			</subsection>
		</section>
	</chapter>
	
	
	<chapter title="Content Repository (sbCR)" id="sbcr">
		<section title="What is a Content Repository?" id="whatiscr">
			<subsection title="Purpose" id="">
				
			</subsection>
			<subsection title="Rough Comparison JCR vs. sbCR" id="">
				- compromise between speed and JCR compatibility
				- DB backed, access possible aside JCR API
				- some things adapted to PHP
				- added functionality leads to restrictions
				- Conclusion: not portable if using the full sbCR API
			</subsection>
		</section>
		<section title="JCR vs. sbCR" id="jcrsbcr">
			<subsection title="Workspaces" id="">
				<info>
					Currently there's basically only one workspace at a time supported.
					You can use more, but they won't be connected.
					This has effects on multiple node usage across workspaces, some other JCR API aspects and versioning when it's impemented.
				</info>
				<todo>
					The performance impact of having several workspaces in one hierarchy table has to be evaluated.
					Additionally, it's not clear how nodes with arbitrary values should be handled.
				</todo>
			</subsection>
			<subsection title="Permissions" id="">
				<caution>
					Repository permissions are currently not supported.
					A valid repository user has full permissions on the whole repository (usually the system connects to the repository).
				</caution>
				<info>
					In terms of managing authorisations, these are handled in the application layer via sbSystem capabilities.
					See $CHAPTER
				</info>
			</subsection>
			<subsection title="Same Name Siblings" id="samenamesiblings">
				<caution>
					Same name siblings are currently not supported.
				</caution>
				<todo>
					This might be easy to implement, extending the internal name by '[#]', where # defaults to 0.
					However, the dependencies in other system parts have to be looked at.
					Additionally, this means the hierarchy table has to contain the internal name because of consistency.
				</todo>
			</subsection>
			<subsection title="Shared Sets" id="">
				<p>
					sbCR supports shared nodes according to the JCR API. However, they always have the same name as it is stored in the node itself, and nodes are managed separately from the workspace hierarchy.
				</p>
				<caution>
					As there is only one instance of a node created in the repository, a name change applies to all nodes in the shared set.
				</caution>
				<todo>
					Supporting shared sets with flexible naming means the hierarchy table has to contain the internal name.
					This has implications on other parts of the system.
				</todo>
			</subsection>
			<subsection title="Mixin Types" id="mixin">
				<p>
					All nodes have (at least) the following mixin types:
				</p>
				<ul>
					<li>mix:created</li>
					<li>mix:lastModified</li>
					<li>mix:referencable</li>
					<li>mix:referencable</li>
					<li>mix:lockable</li>
					<li>mix:referencable</li>
					<li>sb:deleted</li>
					<li>sb:node</li>
				</ul>
				<todo>
					Nodetype inheritance is not fully available right now.
					In order to support it, there are several things needed:
					<ul>
						<li>completing the code dealing with repository 'reflection'</li>
						<li>replacing the current property handling (caching)</li>
						<li>deciding on what should happen with views/actions (do they aggregate? ist that sensible?)</li>
					</ul>
				</todo>
			</subsection>
			<subsection title="Properties" id="properties">
				<p>
					Because of the mandatory mixin types, several properties are mandatory.
				</p>
				<caution>sbCR properties are currently NOT handled as repository items!
					Instead, properties obtained via getProperty() and the like are treated as scalar php variable types.
					This is mainly for performance reasons and for easier handling
				</caution>
			</subsection>
			<subsection id="versioning" title="Versioning">
				<todo>
					The performance impact of having several versions in the repository as well as transporting the version informatione in the hierarchy table has to be evaluated.
					Additionally, it's not clear how nodes with arbitrary values should be handled.
				</todo>
			</subsection>
		</section>
		<section title="Repository Structure" id="structure">
			
		</section>
		<section title="sbCR Repository Constraints and " id="custom">
			
			
		</section>
		<section title="API Changes" id="api">
			
		</section>
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter title="Custom Features" id="viewsactions">
		<section title="Views and Actions" id="concept">
			<subsection title="Content vs. Application Logic?" id="contentlogic">
				<p>
					JCR itself only deals with the data structures stored in the repository, and to some extent also with the content logic (via constraints, references and the like).
					sbCR uses a slightly different approach, it also couples application logic with the nodes.
					This is achieved by describing the different actions that can be 'called' upon the nodes.
				</p>
				<p>
					Actions are what drives any application, may it be the click on a button/link or submitting of a form.
					Every action results in a request sent to the server which sends a corresponding response.
					In a REST environment like the web, everything is built of actions a user can take, even if they are called (periodically) by an AJAX event.
				</p>
				<p>
					The application design should be built according to this premise.
					You are free to use a different approach (TODO: see other chapters), but it is strongly recommended that you describe the objects of the application domain in terms of data and logic.
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection title="What is a View?" id="view">
				<p>
					A view in itself is first and formeost nothing more than a conceptual idea of different means to approach an object.
					For example, think of a folder in an operating system: you can list the files contained in the folder, you can view them in a thumbnail view, or you could take a look at the folder properties.
					This is the exact same object-centric approach solidMatter uses to build up an application.
					But it doesn't stop there, a view may use several actions, e.g. a folder's properties may be displayed, edited or saved.
				</p>
				<p>
					In the application context, views provide a way to group actions together logically, but also in regard of the codebase.
					Usually, there is one class for each view, and this class handles all actions that can called upon a node.
				</p>
				<info>
					Each view defined on a nodetype MAY be displayed in the backend automatically (as a flag TODO: consider authorisation).
					This doesn't make sense on all possible views, so it's up to you to decide which views should be invisible, and what's the most sensible order to display the views in.
				</info>
			</subsection>
			<subsection title="What is an Action?" id="action">
				
			</subsection>
		</section>
		<section id="web20" title="Web 2.0">
			<subsection id="web20_votes" title="Voting/Rating">
				<p>
					
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection id="web20_tags" title="Tags">
				<p>
					
				</p>
			</subsection>
		</section>
		<section id="authorisation" title="Authorisation">
			<subsection title=""></subsection>
		</section>
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter id="sample_application" title="Building A Sample Application">
		<section id="samp_started" title="Getting started">
			
			<subsection id="samp_think" title="Think...">
				<p>
					So, what are you trying to achieve?
					You want to build a simple blog, therefore the required functionality is easily imaginable:
				</p>
				<ul>
					<li>Admins should be able to create, edit and delete blog entries</li>
					<li>Readers should be able to comment</li>
				</ul>
				<p>
					There's also a small, well defined set of things you deal with:
				</p>
				<ul>
					<li>Blog entries</li>
					<li>Comments</li>
				</ul>
			</subsection>
			<subsection id="samp_objects" title="Application Domain Objects">
				<p>
					In order to build this application, you have to model the domain objects you are dealing with, as well as the operations performed on them.
					So let's take a look at the details...
				</p>
				<p>
					A simple blog entry should at least contain the following information:
				</p>
				<ul>
					<li>the title</li>
					<li>the content</li>
					<li>the creator (if we assume it's a blog run by several people)</li>
					<li>the date and time the post was created</li>
					<li>a unique identifier</li>
				</ul>
				<p>
					It should also be viewable, editable, and deletable by the admins in terms of use cases.
					Also anyone can view an entry in the blog.
				</p>
				<p>
					A comment has even less information attached to it in the simplest version:
				</p>
				<ul>
					<li>the comment itself</li>
				</ul>
				<p>
					In terms of functionality, anyone can post a comment, and admins should be able to view, edit and delete comments.
				</p>
				<p>
					As we have seen, there are two objects in the applications domain we have to model.
					But wait, haven't we forgot something?
					As solidMatter is able to run several blogs, we have to model the application itself, too.
					This is just as easy, a blog doesn't need much information for a start:
				</p>
				<ul>
					<li>a title</li>
				</ul>
				<p>
					The blog itself should be able to list all entries, so you can click on a topic and view all details and comments.
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection id="samp_next" title="Next Step">
				<p>
					So now you know what you're dealing with.
					Ideally, you'd now write down all requirements and think about details e.g., how long may a blog entry get?
					But we want to get something on the screen, so we'll skip this part and deal with the details later.
					Time to move to the implementation...
				</p>
			</subsection>
		</section>
		<section id="samp_prepare" title="Preparation">
			<p>
				As you are implementing a new application and not an extension module, you have to put all new stuff into a new namespace to seperate it from the other modules.
				Namespaces should start with a lowercase prefix that applies only to one entity (a person, a company, an organisation).
				Remember, you might not be the only one creating a blog application, e.g. all modules "owned" by the solidMatter project will start with "sb" (for "solidbytes").
				"my" would be a badly chosen prefix in reality, but let's just call the application "myBlog" for now.
			</p>
			<p>
				So you got the namespace, but you need a 'safe' name (all lowercase plus underscore) for it, too.
				This would be "my_blog" according to the guidelines.
			</p>
			<p>
				A module has to provide several mandatory things, e.g. you have to store the scripts, locales etc. in specific folders.
			</p>
			<action>
				Create the following folders:
				<ul>
					<li>&lt;solidMatter&gt;/modules/my_blog</li>
					<li>&lt;solidMatter&gt;/modules/my_blog/scripts_php</li>
					<li>&lt;solidMatter&gt;/interface/locales/my_blog</li>
					<li>&lt;solidMatter&gt;/interface/themes/_default/my_blog/</li>
					<li>&lt;solidMatter&gt;/interface/themes/_default/my_blog/xsl/</li>
				</ul>
			</action>	
			<info>
				You might need to create more folders depending on what you need to provide (custom icons, CSS stylesheets and the like).
				More details on the default directory structure can be found in $CHAPTER
			</info>
		</section>
		<section id="samp_repository" title="Setting up the Repository items">
			<p>
				The necessary repository set-up is done best in these steps (subject to change, when we support the JCR API for repository administration):
			</p>
			<ul>
				<li>creating the nodetypes</li>
				<li>creating the nodetype's properties</li>
				<li>creating the nodetype's views</li>
				<li>creating the nodetype's actions</li>
				<li>associating modes with the nodetypes</li>
				<li>more...</li>
			</ul>
			<subsection id="samp_nodetypes" title="Nodetypes">
				<p>
					First, you should create the nodetypes for your application. Luckily, there is already a comment nodetype that meets our expectations, sbSystem:Comment, so we'll leave that one out.
				</p>
				<info>
					In order to not interfere with other modules, you might like to build your own comment nodetype, just in case requirements change and you need things the internal comment doesn't provide.
				</info>
				<action>
					Insert the following entries into the nodetypes table:
					<ul>
						<li>myBlog:Blog</li>
						<li>myBlog:Entry</li>
					</ul>
				</action>
			</subsection>
			<subsection id="samp_properties" title="Properties">
				<p>
					Next on the list should be the properties that are associated with the nodetypes.
					Again, luckily solidMatter provides us with a set of prepared set of properties (see $CHAPTER).
					As the nodetype already stores most of the needed information, we are just left with the content property.
				</p>
				<action>
					Insert the following entries into the properties table:
					<ul>
						<li>myBlog:Entry content</li>
					</ul>
				</action>
			</subsection>
			<subsection id="samp_views" title="Views">
				
				<action>
					Insert the following entries into the views table:
					<ul>
						<li>myBlog:Blog properties</li>
						<li>myBlog:Blog index</li>
						<li>myBlog:Entry properties</li>
						<li>myBlog:Entry comments</li>
					</ul>
				</action>
			</subsection>
			<subsection id="samp_actions" title="Actions">
				
			</subsection>
		</section>
		<section id="" title="">
			
		</section>
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter title="Coding Guidelines" id="codingguidelines">
		<p>
			In order to keep the code readable and consistent, there are a number of coding guidelines described in this chapter.
			You MUST stick to these rules if you are contributing to the solidMatter core or any of the sb*-modules (provided by respectively under development lead by solidbytes). 
			You SHOULD stick to these rules if you are developing a 3rd-party-module for solidMatter.
		</p>
		<info>
			Rules exist to be broken. No, seriously, there are exceptions from these rules, but keep in mind that they are very rare, and MUST serve the readability or have a really good reason.
		</info>
		<section title="Versioning" id="code_versioning">
			<p>
				There are 5 types of versions to be maintained in solidMatter, Module- resp. release-, API-, locale-, theme- and file-versions.
				Versioning uses a fixed scheme, which MUST be followed even for 3rd-party-modules.
				The scheme contains information on major version, features, bugfixes and release states.
				Module (=release), API, locale and theme versions are not coupled in any way to source code versions.
			</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Version: 0-# (# is not limited)</li>
				<li>Subversion: 00-99 (increased with every release that contains added features or API changes)</li>
				<li>Bugfixversion: 00-99 (increased with every release that contains bugfixes, this number is reset on changes to version or subversion)</li>
				<li>Release State (optional): one of the following - alpha, beta, rc# (# is not limited)</li>
			</ul>
			<p>
				Examples:
			</p>
			<ul>
				<li>0.04.02alpha</li>
				<li>1.00.00</li>
				<li>1.02.04beta</li>
				<li>1.02.07rc2</li>
				<li>1.05.13</li>
				<li>12.08.00</li>
			</ul>
		</section>
		<section title="Variable Naming" id="variablenaming">
			<p>Variables SHOULD always indicate their proposed type as lowercase prefix, followed by the self explanatory name: "$prefixSelfExplanatoryName".
			The well-known Prefixes for scalar types are:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>i: Integer</li>
				<li>s: String</li>
				<li>f: Float</li>
				<li>a: Array</li>
				<li>h: Ressource Handle</li>
			</ul>
			<p>For objects:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>node: sbNode or sbCRNode</li>
				<li>ni: sbNodeIterator</li>
				<li>cache: any kind of cache object</li>
				<li>elem: DOMElement</li>
				<li>dom: DOMDocument or derived class</li>
				<li>form: sbDOMForm</li>
				<li>view: sbView or derived class</li>
				<li>o: unknown/unspecified object</li>
			</ul>
			<info>
				Exceptions:
				<ul>
					<li>$_REQUEST/$_RESPONSE: global request/response in solidMatter</li>
					<li>$i, $j, etc.: loop iterators</li>
					<li>$e: catched exception</li>
				</ul>
			</info>
		</section>
		<section title="Code Formatting" id="codeformatting">
			<subsection title="Indenting" id="">
				<p>
					Indenting SHOULD always be done according to best-practices (indenting codeblocks) using tabs.
					Each tab uses the equivalent space to 4 spaces.
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection title="Bracketing" id="">
				<p>
					All code blocks SHOULD be contained in brackets, even if they only consist of one command.
					The opening bracket SHOULD be on the same line as the control flow structure (for, if, while...).
				</p>
				<code>// Correct
while (!$asleep) {
	$sheep++;
}
					
// Wrong
while (!$asleep)
{
	$sheep++;
}
while (!$asleep)
	$sheep++;</code>
				<info>
					There may be sensible exceptions to that rule, when a series of short commands (e.g. defines) occur or when the unary operator is used.
				</info>
			</subsection>
			<subsection title="Bracketing" id=""></subsection>
			<subsection title="Comments and File Structure" id="">
				<p>
					The file structure, and along with it the basic commenting structure applies to all files that contain only one class.
				</p>
				<code><![CDATA[<?php

//------------------------------------------------------------------------------
/**
* @package	{package name}[{subpackage name}]
* @author	{author's name}
* @version	{version}
*/
//------------------------------------------------------------------------------

import("myModule:foo");
import("myModule:bar");
				
//------------------------------------------------------------------------------
/**
*/
class sbView_{nodetype}_{view} extends sbView {
	
	//--------------------------------------------------------------------------
	/**
	* 
	* @param 
	* @return 
	*/
	public function myMethod() {
		
		// some code
		
	}
	
}

?>]]></code>
			</subsection>
		</section>
		<section id="sessionusage" title="Session Usage">
			<p>The session can be used to store various information. This chapter explains what different modes of access exist.</p>
			<subsection title="Per Nodetype Settings" id="pernodetype">
				<p>The keys for the information should be named like this: "module:nodetype:setting".
				Example:</p>
				<code>sbSession::addData('sbSystem:Folder:defaultView', $sView);</code>
			</subsection>
		</section>
		<section id="filesystemstructure" title="Filesystem Structure">
			<p>
				The filesystem structure of solidMatter contains mandatory and optional files/folders: 
			</p>
			<ul>
				{solidMatter root directory}
				<li>_cache (mandatory, should be used to store stuff cached in local filesystem)</li>
				<li>_config (mandatory)
					<ul>
						<li>controller.xml (mandatory, configuration for controller layer)</li>
						<li>interface.xml (mandatory, configuration for interface layer)</li>
						<li>repositories.xml (mandatory, configuration for sbCR repositories)</li>
					</ul>
				</li>
				<li>_logs (mandatory, stores all logfiles generated in application layer)</li>
				<li>_temp (mandatory, used for temporary files, uploads etc.)</li>
				<li>interface
				<ul>
					<li>locales
						<ul>
							<li>{Module}
							<ul>
								<li>base_{language}.xml (mandatory, base locale for the module)</li>
								<li>help_{language}.xml (optional, help texts for the module if used)</li>
							</ul>
							</li>
						</ul>
					</li>
					<li>themes
					<ul>
						<li>{Theme}
						<ul>
							<li>{Module}
							<ul>
								<li>css (stylesheets used by the module for the current theme)</li>
								<ul>
									<li>styles.css (mandatory for admin backend, this is the stylesheet that will be loaded automatically)</li>
								</ul>
								<li>icons (all icons for nodetypes owned by this module, also additional icons if necessary)</li>
								<li>images (optional, images needed for the module)</li>
								<li>xsl (mandatory, contains all stylesheets defined for the views/actions of the module)</li>
							</ul>
							</li>
						</ul>
						</li>
					</ul>
					</li>
				</ul>
				</li>
				<li>modules
				<ul>
					<li>{Module}
					<ul>
						<li>bin (optional)</li>
						<li>data (optional)</li>
						<li>documentation (mandatory, developer and user manuals)</li>
						<li>scripts_php (mandatory, all scripts used by the module)
						<ul>
							<li>external (optional, all external libraries used by the module)</li>
						</ul>
						</li>
					</ul>
					</li>
				</ul>
				</li>
				<li>controller.php</li>
				<li>interface.php</li>
			</ul>
			<info>
				Please note that in case of a split tier environment (interface and backend hosted seperately), the following directories/files have to be available to the interface layer:
				<ul>
					<li>soldMatter/interface.php</li>
					<li>soldMatter/_config/interface.xml</li>
					<li>soldMatter/interface/</li>
					<li>soldMatter/modules/sb_system (must be available in both tiers!)</li>
				</ul>
			</info>
			<caution>
				Split tier setups have not been tested for a while.
				There are DEFINATELY several bugs that prevent such a setup in current state!
			</caution>
			<todo>
				Bring split tier setups in a usable state again.
			</todo>
		</section>
	</chapter>
	
	<chapter title="Appendix" id="appendix">
		<section id="add_docu" title="Additional Documentation">
			
		</section>
		<section id="Roadmap" title="roadmap">
			<subsection id="v1" title="Initial Release">
				<ul>
					<li>sbCR: locking</li>
					<li>sbCR: rudimentary repository administration</li>
					<li>sbCR: nodetype inheritance</li>
					<li>sbCR: namespace registry</li>
					<li>sbCR: property constraints</li>
					<li>solidMatter: guided install tool</li>
					<li>solidMatter: module install/uninstall</li>
					<li>solidMatter: extensible form inputtypes</li>
					<li>solidMatter: extensible handlers</li>
					<li>solidMatter: more flexible app positioning (relative to domain root directory)</li>
					<li>solidMatter: user-specific registry values (incl. administration)</li>
				</ul>
			</subsection>
			<subsection id="vx" title="Future Releases">
				<ul>
					<li>sbCR: XPath</li>
					<li>sbCR: XQuery</li>
					<li>sbCR: versioning</li>
					<li>sbCR: visitors</li>
					<li>sbCR: connected workspaces</li>
					<li>sbCR: full repository administration</li>
					<li>sbCR: full property/node constraints</li>
					<li>sbCR: lifecycle transitions</li>
				</ul>
			</subsection>
		</section>
		<section id="history" title="History" >
			<subsection title="0.50.00 alpha" id="05alpha">
				<ul>
					<li>[STATE] initial state, work in progress</li>
					<li>[FEATURE] ~50% JSR-283 compliant API</li>
					<li>[FEATURE] ability to define views and actions on nodetypes</li>
					<li>[FEATURE] each node may have tags assigned to it, tags are workspace-global</li>
					<li>[FEATURE] each node may be rated, rates are stored with user information</li>
				</ul>
			</subsection>
		</section>
	</chapter>
	
</doc>